U. Roberto (Robin) Romano Papers 2008.0006
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series III: Migrant Labor, 1972-2011
  This series includes photographs, negatives, clippings, notes, publications, pamphlets, correspondence, optical and magnetic disks, and moving images relating to migrant and child labor in the United States and Mexico, including material from the documentary The Harvest/La Cosecha.
  - 40th Annual National Migrant Education Conference, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Adelante!, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Association of Farmworker Opportunity Programs (AFOP), 1998-2002 (Box 15, Folder 28, Box 25, Folder 197)
  - AFOP National Conference, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - AFOP Washington Newsline, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - AG Laws and BG, 2010 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Children in the Fields Interview Transcripts and Logs, 2008-2009 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Children's Act for Responsible Employment (CARE), 2010 (Box 16, Folder 6, Folder 10)
  - Farmworker Education and Service Program, undated
  - Farmworker Education and Service Program Calendar, 2008-2009 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Florida Exmeplary Migrant Student, Parents, and Staff, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Florida Migrant Education Program Directory, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - H-2A Program, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Harvest of Hope Foundation, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Licensed Agricultural Camps, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Migrant Newsletter, 2008-2009 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Migrant Workers Background, 2008-2009 (Box 17, Folder 8, Box 16, Folder 27)
  - New Horizon, 2007-2008 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Optical disk, 2008 (Box 14, Other AFOP Fine Cut: Children in the Fields)
  - Rural Opportunities, Inc. (ROI), 2007 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Texas Negatives, 2003 (Box 3, Other Texas Selects - SC, Other Texas B&W/Color - SC)
  - US Farm Workers, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - USA Child Labor, 14th Amendment, New Colonialism, 2005-2009 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Harvest/La Cosecha, Bulk, 2007-2010; 1972-2011
    - Application Essays, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Background, 2007-2009 (Box 18, Folder 14, Box 17, Folder 13)
    - BG Current, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - BG Speeches and Notes, original contacts, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Bite Selections, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - BU US-TX, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - California (empty), undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Contact Sheets and Schedule, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Contacts, 2008-2009 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 2008-2010 (Box 16, Folder 16, Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Cosecha/Harvest, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Credits, 2009-2010 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Diaries and Interviews to file, 2009-2010 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Department of Labor Panel and SCS001 Social Sustainability Subcommittee Research, 2008-2009 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Draft Speeches, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Florida, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Harvest 1, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Harvest 2 Logs and Transcripts, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Harvest/Cosecha Releases, 2007-2009 (Box 13, Folder 6, Box 17, Folder 4, Folder 2)
    - Harvest Fall 2008 General (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Negatives, 2007 (Box 16, Other Harvest MN 1 & 2 - OH 1)
    - Harvest - N.C., 2008 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Harvest - Orland, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - HRW Shot List MI, undated (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Interview Transcripts, 2009-2010 (Box 18, Folder 40, Box 16, Folder 4, Folder 11, Folder 8)
    - Interviews Volum 1 HBO Cast Initial Interviews, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Interviews Volume 2 Lopez/Gomez, 2009-2010 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Interviews Volume 3 Sanchez, 2009-2010 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Interviews Volume 4 Huapilla, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Interviews Volume 5 Rios, Garza, Mojica, and Torres, 2009-2010 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Logs, Diaraies and Updates, 2009-2010 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Logs, Harvest 1 Tape 1-13, Transcripts 1,2,9-11, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - MI August Diary, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Moorhead, MN Migrant Workers, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Moving Images (6), undated (Box 14)
    - Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 10, Box 18, Folder 22, Box 13, Folder 2, Box 20, Folder 13, Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Optical Disks (82), 2007-2011 (Box 18, Box 16, Box 14, Box 17, Box 11)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Promotional Material, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Questions, undated, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 7, Box 18, Folder 32, Folder 27)
    - Research, 1972-2007 (Box 13, Folder 3, Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Script and Edit Notes, 2010-2011 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Scripts, 2007-2008 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Shoot Budget, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Storybooks, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Texas, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Texas Notes, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Trailer, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - University of Connecticut Flyer, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - Untitled Print, undated (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Winter 2009/2010 Update (Box 16, Folder 30)
- Series IV: Human Rights, 1989-2010
  This series includes photographs, negatives, clippings, notes, publications, pamphlets, correspondence, optical and magnetic disks, posters, and moving images relating to various human rights issues. Material for An Indifferent World, Children in the Crossfire, and The Hunger Project are included here. Subjects include globalization, forced labor, fair trade, the cotton and coffee industries, and socially responsible business among other human rights interests.
  - Africa: Articles, 1999-2003 (Box 23, Folder 72)
  - Amnesty International, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 156, Box 19, Folder 38)
  - An Action Plan for the Rehabilitation of Bonded Labourers in Karnataka, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - An Indifferent World, 2006-2007
    - Negatives, 2006 (Box 4, Other IW/Sudan)
    - Optical Disk, 2007 (Box 11, Other Indifferent World Select Photographs - Ocampo Sterling)
  - "And by that time it was too late to do anything,", undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Anti-Slavery International, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 154, Folder 155)
  - Articles, 1999-2001 (Box 25, Folder 182, Folder 179, Folder 178, Folder 180)
  - Asia, 1999-2001 (Box 23, Folder 112, Folder 90, Folder 109)
  - Asia: Articles, 1998-2000 (Box 23, Folder 85, Folder 88, Folder 108)
  - Asia: Copy of Books and Articles, undated, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 98)
  - Asia: Journals and Articles, 1999-2000 (Box 23, Folder 91, Folder 92)
  - Asia: Reports and Articles, 1998-2002 (Box 23, Folder 95, Folder 99, Folder 93)
  - Barnen & VI, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Beyond the French Press, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Bonhoeffer Phenomenon, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Chapter 8 of Book, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 174)
  - Children in Armed Conflict, 1998-2003 (Box 25, Folder 184, Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Children in Jeopardy, undated (Box 25, Folder 186)
  - Children in the Crossfire, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Otunnu/United Nations, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Questions for Interviews, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Coffee in Kenya, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Coffee Kids: Grounds for Hope, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Coffee: Poverty and Globalization, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 173, Folder 172)
  - Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR), 2005 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Debt Boomerang, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Exhibitions, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 175)
  - Extra! Magazine, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 202)
  - Fair Trade, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 171)
  - Footprints, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 200)
  - Globalization: Articles, 1998-2001 (Box 20, Folder 22, Box 25, Folder 168, Folder 176)
  - Globalization: Articles and Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 167)
  - Globalization Negatives, 1998 (Box 8, Other Globalization Selects, Other Globalization Color, Box 4, Other Globalization B&W)
  - Globalization Photographs (22), 1998 (Box 8, Other Globalization Selects - 1998)
  - GoodWeave Promo Miami Exhibit, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Certificate in Human Rights at the University of Connecticut, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Hans Kung, 1993-1999 (Box 25, Folder 185)
  - Hidden Slaves: Forced Labor in the United States, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Human Rights Watch, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 183)
  - Humanities, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hunger Project, [1999]-2000
    - The Hunger Project, [1999] (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Negatives, 2000 (Box 2, Other India Hunger Project, Box 9, Other India Assorted, Box 3, Other India B&W - SC)
  - India Cotton Farmer Suicides, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - India Forum, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 86)
  - India Negatives, 1997 (Box 8, Other India 97 To Sort, Other India 1997 Color (7159-7650), Box 4, Other India 1997 Selects)
  - India Photographs (36), 1997-2000 (Box 4, Other India 1997 Selects, Box 9, Other India Assorted 2000)
  - International Labor Rights Fund Posters, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Labor and Global Trade Clippings, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Let's Make a Deal: Beltway Edition, 2009 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Magnetic Disks (2), 1999 (Box 11)
  - Mahbub ul Haq, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 33, Folder 46)
  - Moving Images (31), 1989-2005 (Box 5, Box 9, Box 6, Box 11)
  - Newsletters, 2007-2008 (Box 24, Folder 151)
  - Newsweek: How to Heal the World, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - On Shaky Grounds: Why Coffee Farmers Need Your Help, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Online Newsletters, 2001-2004 (Box 26, Folder 205)
  - Optical Disks (15), 2001-2008 (Box 14, Box 11)
  - Pakistan Negatives, 1995-1997 (Box 10, Other Pakistan 1996 Chromes, Other Pakistan 1996 Color (6168-7138), Box 7, Other Pakistan 1996 LOL Mangrio, Box 8, Other Pakistan 1997 B&W (001-0230), Other Pakistan 1996 B&W (0130-0202), Other Pakistan Bazar Chromes, Other Pakistan Selects)
  - Pakistan Photographs (120), 1996-1997 (Box 7, Other Pakistan 1996 LOL Mangrio, Other Pakistan 1996 B&W (0130-0202), Box 8, Other Pakistan 1997 B&W (001-0230), Other Pakistan Selects 1996-97, Box 10, Other Pakistan 1996 Color (6168-7138), Other Pakistan 1997 Color (0532-8943))
  - Pamphlets, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 204)
  - Paying the Price, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Proceedings of the Seminar on River Crises in South Asia, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Reports, 1997-2003 (Box 25, Folder 181, Folder 177)
  - Research, 1992-2007 (Box 17, Folder 9, Box 21, Folder 3, Box 19, Folder 37, Folder 73, Folder 72, Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Shoe Factory Workers Thumbnails and Photograph, undated (Box 19, Folder 71)
  - Socially Responsible Business, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 170, Folder 169)
  - South/Central America: Articles and Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 25, Folder 187)
  - Sri Lanka: Report, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 96)
  - Text of Bill Clinton Speech, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 196)
  - The Economist, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 26, Box 18, Folder 10)
  - The New York Times, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 194)
  - The New York Times Magazine: The Perfect Drought, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Progress of Nations, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 158)
  - Thirteenth Amendment Research, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Trafficking in Persons Report, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - United States: Articles and Journals, 1991-2002 (Box 25, Folder 199, Folder 192, Folder 193, Folder 195)
  - U.S. Department of Labor, undated (Box 25, Folder 198)
  - Utne Magazine, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Washington Report on Middle East, 1997-1999 (Box 23, Folder 84, Folder 89)
  - We the Peoples, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - White Gold: The True Cost of Cotton, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - World Education Forum, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 203)
- Series V: Administrative, 1998-2010
  This series includes administrative notes, pamphlets, correspondence, and optical and magnetic disks relating to Romano’s various projects. Subjects include equipment care, legal considerations, business contacts and relations, letters of appreciation, educational opportunities, and Romano’s website. Some material in the correspondence, interviews and transcripts, notes, and questions files may relate specifically to projects in other series.
  - Association of Small Foundations: Members by State, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Airport X-ray, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Columbia/dKv, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Copyright, 2002-2003 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Editorial Plan for Media Voices for Children, undated (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - General Contact List, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Headwaters, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Interviews and Transcripts, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Letters of Appreciation, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Magnetic Disks (12), undated (Box 11)
  - Media Curriculum for Teenagers, undated (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 206)
  - Moving Images (2), 2002-2007 (Box 5, Box 14)
  - Notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Optical Disks (52), 2000-2008 (Box 11)
  - Questions, undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Reception to Honor Pharis J. Harvey, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Robin Romano's Personal Notes, undated, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Romano Equipment List, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Television, 1999-2000 (Box 26, Folder 207)
  - Temple of Understanding, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Tubman Shooting Plan, 2010 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Videographers Newsletter, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 201)
  - Washington Itinerary, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Website - Romano Productions, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)